Mankind was born on Earth. It was never meant to die here.
Interstellar is a adventure, drama, science fiction
film directed by Christopher Nolan.
The adventures of a group of explorers who make use of a newly discovered wormhole to surpass the
limitations on human space travel and conquer the vast distances involved in an interstellar voyage.
Cooper, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Brand, played by Anne Hathaway.
Professor Brand, played by Michael Caine.
Murph, played by Jessica Chastain.
Tom, played by Casey Affleck.
Doyle, played by Wes Bentley.
Interstellar is a 2014 epic science fiction film directed by Christopher Nolan,
who co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Jonathan Nolan.
It features an ensemble cast led by Matthew McConaughey, Anne Hathaway,
Jessica Chastain, Bill Irwin, Ellen Burstyn, and Michael Caine.
Set in a dystopian future where Earth is suffering from catastrophic blight and famine, the film follows a
group of astronauts who travel through a wormhole near Saturn in search of a new home for mankind.
The screenplay had its origins in a script that Jonathan had developed in
2007 and was originally set to be directed by Steven Spielberg.
Theoretical physicist Kip Thorne was an executive producer and scientific consultant
on the film, and wrote the tie-in book The Science of Interstellar.
It was Lynda Obst's final film as producer before her death.
Cinematographer Hoyte van Hoytema shot it on 35 mm film in the
Panavision anamorphic format and IMAX 70 mm.
Filming began in late 2013 and took place in Alberta, Klaustur, and Los Angeles.
Interstellar uses extensive practical and miniature effects, and
the company DNEG created additional visual effects.
Interstellar premiered at the TCL Chinese Theatre on October 26, 2014, and was released in theaters in the United States on November
5, and in the United Kingdom on November 7, with Paramount Pictures distributing in the United States and Warner Bros.
Pictures distributing in international markets.
In the United States, it was first released on film stock,
expanding to venues using digital projectors.
It was a commercial success, grossing $681 million worldwide during its initial theatrical run, and $773.8
million worldwide with subsequent releases, making it the 10th-highest-grossing film of 2014.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
Among its various accolades, Interstellar was nominated for five awards
at the 87th Academy Awards, winning Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of rescue, future, spacecraft, race
against time, artificial intelligence (a.i.).
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.